Guide to the Two World Wars Collection, 1918-1949.
Two World Wars Collection, 1918-1949
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Two World Wars Collection, 1918-1949.
6493.
1.2 cubic ft.
Newspapers, magazines.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Newspapers and magazines reporting major events during World War I and II.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Newspapers and magazines reporting the Armistice being signed (Nov. 1918) and major events during World War II (1941-49), including the Washington Times Herald; Washington Post; New York Times; Baltimore News-Post; Washington Daily News; Philadelphia Inquirer; Daily Mirror; Baltimore American; Evening Star; Minneapolis Journal; Wisconsin State Journal; Madison Democrat; Yank: the Army Weekly and The Voice of Victory.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Press coverage.; United States--History--1918-1949--Press coverage.; World war, 1939-1945--Newspapers.; World war, 1914-1918--Newspapers.; World war, 1939-1945--Magazines.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Newspapers from World War I and II
  - Wisconsin State Journal, Nov. 7, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Madison Democrat, Nov. 8, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Wisconsin State Journal, Nov. 11, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Minneapolis Journal, Mar. 4, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Minneapolis Journal, Mar. 6, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore News-Post, Jan. 20, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald - Washington, June 8, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore American, Sept. 3, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore News-Post, Sept. 9, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Dec. 8, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Washington Daily News, Dec. 8, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Washington Post, Dec. 8, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore News-Post, Dec. 8, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore News-Post, Dec. 11, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Washington Daily News, Jan. 6, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore News-Post, Apr. 18, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Washington Daily News, Aug. 8, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Washington Daily News, Aug. 19, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Washington Daily News, Nov. 11, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Dec. 6, 1942 (Box 1)
  - La Voix - France, Jan. 1943 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Jan. 27, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald - Washington, July 10, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Philadelphia Inquirer, July 11, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Washington Daily News, July 16, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald - Washington, July 19, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Daily Mirror - Washington, July 26, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Washington Post, July 26, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald - Washington, July 26, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Washington Daily News, Aug. 17, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Washington Post, Sept. 3, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Washington Daily News, Sept. 3, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Sept. 3, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Evening Star - Washington, Sept. 3, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Sept. 8, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Washington Daily News, Sept. 8, 1943 (Box 1)
  - New York Daily News, Sept. 9, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Daily Mirror, Sept. 13, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Washington Daily News, Oct. 13, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Evening Star - Washington, Dec. 6, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Times Herald - Washington, June 6, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Washington Post, June 6, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Philadelphia Inquirer, June 6, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Washington Post, Apr. 13, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Apr. 13, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Apr. 14, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Evening Star - Washington, Apr. 14, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Times Herald - Washington, May 1, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Evening Star - Washington, May 7, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Aug. 8, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Washington Daily News, Aug. 14, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Evening Star, Aug. 14, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Aug. 15, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Times Herald - Washington, Jan. 20, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Washington Daily News, Jan. 20, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Post Standard - Syracuse, N.Y., 1914-08-03 (Folder 1)
- Magazines from World War II
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, June 6, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Jan. 30, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Feb. 6, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, July 7, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Mar. 17, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, July 14, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, July 21, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, July 28, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Aug. 4, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Aug. 11, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Aug. 18, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Aug. 25, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Sept. 1, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Sept. 8, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Sept. 15, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Sept. 22, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Sept. 29, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Nov. 3, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Nov. 10, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, May 11, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, June 1, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Yank - the Army Weekly, Sept. 7, 1945 (Box 2)
  - The Voice of Victory: British War Office official account of the Battle of Egypt, 1943 (Box 2)